Guide to the Priscilla Morgan Papers, 1910-2014 (bulk 1945-2014)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Priscilla Morgan Papers
1910-2014
1945-2014
Morgan, Priscilla, 1919-2014
18.75 cubic feet (48 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The Priscilla Morgan Papers document the career and collaborative efforts of a New York-based international arts administrator, producer and emissary of arts and culture. The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, subject files, travel files, maps, and photograph albums.
Biographical Note
Priscilla Morgan (1919-2014) attended Vassar College from 1937 to 1939. She served as a commanding officer in the United States Women's Naval Reserve during World War II, where one of her notable accomplishments was producing a concert by Frank Sinatra in 1943. Following her service in the Navy, she launched her career as a radio producer in NYC and went on to become a theatrical agent for writers, directors and producers.
In the mid 1950s European travel and business became central to her career, and during this period, Morgan met the composer Gian Carlo Menotti, founder of the Spoleto Festival (Festival of the Two Worlds), which later developed into the Spoleto Festival USA (Charleston, North Carolina). Menotti and Morgan became collaborators and proponents of a legacy of performing and visual artists through their co-direction of the festival. At this time, Morgan also became involved in live television and continued as a theatrical agent at William Morris Agency until her full-time association in the mid 1960s laying the ground work for the Spoleto Festival. In years following, Morgan's partnership as a confidant and advisor to the sculptor Isamu Noguchi became central to her life, as she guided public commissions and varied projects for the renowned artist. Her relationship with Noguchi lasted until his death in 1988.
A long-standing and influential New York cultural figure, Morgan's collaborative projects involved a wide range of performing and visual artists. She cultivated formidable networks of artistic liaisons, with both artists and philanthropists, during her lengthy career as producer, festival director, and as board member of the Noguchi Museum until the time of her death.
Scope and Content Note
The Priscilla Morgan Papers document the robust career of a producer and advocate of the performing, visual and literary arts both in New York City, Europe and Japan. The papers document her contributions as a producer, theatrical agent, philanthropic promoter, festival administrator, museum board member and seminal host within wide-reaching New York cultural circles.
The collection consists mainly of subject files (1932 – 2014), as created by Morgan's office, and correspondence files which contain professional and personal correspondence with performing and visual artists, colleagues and philanthropists in the performing arts. Subject files document Ms. Morgan's productions in theater, film, television and visual arts from the mid 1950s until her death in 2014.
Morgan's involvement with Isamu Noguchi and her commitment to the museum in his name, figure prominently in the papers. Her partnership with Noguchi spanned between the personal and the public, as documented in both the collection's subject files and correspondence files. Subject files also document collaborative works with artists including R. Buckminster Fuller, Willem deKooning, Martin Manulis, Robert Wilson, Rene Bouche and others.
Access
Material relating to settlement of the Noguchi estate (folders 21.1-21.3) are restricted through 2037. Otherwise, this collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
De Kooning, Lisa, 1956 - 2012; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983; Gilchrist, Ellen, 1935-; Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-1988
Organizations:
Spoleto Festival U.S.A.‏; Isamu Noguchi Foundation and Garden Museum‏
Subjects:
Art patrons--United States--Biography; Arts, American--New York (State)--New York
VCL Categories
Art and Artists; Music; Travel
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2019.
Acquisition Information
Bequest of the estate of Priscilla Morgan, 2017.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series; Subject Files (1932 – 2014), Correspondence (1945 – 2014), Photographs (1910 – 2009). Subject Files contain fourteen subseries, as defined by the creator.
Correspondence files of substantial volume are arranged by year, otherwise the series is arranged alphabetically by name, as arranged by the creator.
Series List
- Series I. Subject Files, 1932-2014; (Boxes 1-31 and 43-46 )
  Subject files reflect the filing system of Ms. Morgan’s office, the majority of folders arranged by their original folder titles. The files document Morgan’s business acumen, and often include budget drafts of both visual and performing art projects, numerous dinner party seating charts, guest lists, menus and event logistics, extensive phone logs, and travel itineraries, dating from her earliest days as a radio/theater/television producer, through to her final years serving on the board of the Noguchi Museum. Business files track Ms. Morgan’s earliest years as a young producer for William Morris Agency, for William Liebling, and on through to her development of her own production agencies, Drunk With Love, and MPM Productions. Files document her negotiations both on behalf of her clients, as well as her own personal advancement in the field.
  Spoleto Festival USA files document the festival’s earliest years in Charleston, North Carolina, including initial fundraising efforts to raise capital in support of the festival mission. Logistical files document itineraries and scheduling of some of the festival’s earliest performers, visual artists and speakers, e.g. Philip Glass, Buckminster Fuller, and Robert Wilson.
  Art collection files contain documentation of Morgan’s personal collected artworks, including loans, consignments and sales agreements. Early efforts to bring the Spoleto Festival to the USA is documented in the Harlem Theater Workshop files, illustrating Morgan and Menotti’s failed attempt in launching the festival in Harlem.
  Subject files document correspondence and collaborative efforts with Gian Carlo Menotti (founder of the Spoleto Festival in Italy and the United States), Isamu Noguchi, and R. Buckminster Fuller. The Noguchi files reflect the artist’s long-standing reliance on Morgan to execute his creative vision when negotiating commissions for new works. A limited number of files (here and in correspondence files) include handwritten notations by Noguchi, in particular, a draft artist statement regarding Akari Light Sculptures. Noguchi Museum files illustrate Morgan’s role as a board member, fundraiser, and advisor for the Noguchi estate, through to the end of Morgan’s life.
  Travel files, some including travel for William Morris Agency, include detailed documentation of international travel logistics, itineraries, budgets, agendas, correspondence, entertainment budgets, and letters of introduction, providing detailed insight into how business was conducted and managed by a young woman managing a business in the mid 1950s. Travel files often include correspondence.
  The subject files are arranged alphabetically into fourteen subseries as defined by the creator:
  Art Collection
  Biographical
  Drunk With Love Productions
  Events
  Fuller, R. Buckminster
  General
  Harlem Theatre Workshop
  Legal
  Menotti
  MPM Productions
  Noguchi, Isamu
  Noguchi Museum
  Spoleto Festival
  Travel
- Series II. Correspondence, 1945-2014; (Boxes 32-43)
  Correspondence files reflect Morgan’s own filing system, mainly arranged chronologically, in addition to select files arranged by name, as determined by Morgan’s office. Correspondents include performing and visual artists, as well as philanthropic collaborators involved in the New York City and European art world.
  Spoleto office correspondence provides documentation of the festival’s earliest efforts with logistics and correspondents with artists, VIPs and festival administrators.
  A limited number of correspondence files include carbon copies of Ms. Morgan’s originating letters.
- Series III. Photographs, 1910-2009; (Boxes 47-48)
  Collection includes early photographic prints of the Morgan family, photographs from travels with Isamu Noguchi, copy prints of Noguchi as a child, as well as images documenting Morgan’s business travels both in Europe and Japan.
Container List
- Series I. Subject Files
  - ART COLLECTION
    - Appraisals, 1958-1973 (1.1)
    - Consignments, loans, 1960- 1979 (1.2)
    - de Kooning, 2008 (1.3)
    - de Kooning authentication, 1985 (1.4)
    - Loan Agreements, invoices, 1992-2013 (1.5)
    - Sales agreements, consignments, 1990-2006 (1.6)
    - Sales, purchases, 1955-2005 (1.7 - 1.8)
    - Sales, Noguchi, Circles, 2008-2014 (1.9)
  - BIOGRAPHICAL
    - Columbia University, American Literature, Henry Loomis lesson plan, undated (43.1)
    - Passports, IDs, Episcopal Church Confirmation, Birth Certificate, 1933-1996 (1.10)
    - Press clippings, 1945, 1977-2004 (1.11)
    - Profile of Priscilla Morgan, TS, New York Woman Magazine, 1986 September (1.12)
    - U.S. Naval Reserve, personnel files, press clippings, 1943-1955 (1.13 - 1.15)
  - DRUNK WITH LOVE
    - Ehrin, Kerry, contracts, correspondence, 1990-1991 (2.1 - 2.2)
    - Finances, 1988-1989 (2.3)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, casting - Nora Jane, 1987-1988 (2.4)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, press clippings, 2000 (2.5)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, contract negotiations, 1986-2004 (2.6 - 2.7)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, correspondence, 1987-2011 (2.8)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, literary options, 1988-1992 (2.9)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, writings, undated (2.10 - 2.11)
    - Goldstone, Patricia, contract, script analysis, 1988-1989 (2.12)
    - Goldstone, Patricia, legal notes, 1987-1990 (3.1)
    - Horowitz, Rachael, notes, memos, 1992-1997 (3.2)
    - Interscope Communications, contract, 1989-1991 (3.3 - 3.5)
    - Interscope Communications, correspondence, memos, 1990-1992 (3.6)
    - Manulis, Martin, notes, memos, 1986-1989 (3.7)
    - Mrs. Claus, film production, 1988-1996 (3.8)
    - Notes, ideas, 1987-1992 (3.9)
    - Script analysis, Kerry Ehrin, 1990 (3.10)
    - Script draft, Ehrin, 1990-1994 (3.11 - 4.2)
    - Script, Goldstone, Gilchrist, 1994 (4.3)
    - Story treatments, undated (4.4)
    - Studio correspondence, 1987-1989 (4.5)
    - Studio rejections, 1988-1989 (4.6)
    - Travel, California, 1988 (4.7)
    - Travel, Los Angeles, 1988-1990 (4.8)
    - Travel, New Orleans, 1989 (4.9)
    - Writers for consideration, 1987-1989 (4.10)
  - EVENTS
    - Apollo 12 launch viewing, 1970 November (5.1)
    - Beadleston wedding, 2003 March (5.2)
    - Benefit Concert for the Homeless of NYC, 1989 January (5.3)
    - Dinner parties - planning, logistics, seating charts, 1953-2011 (5.4 - 5.11)
    - Glass, Philip, benefit, 2005 May (5.12)
    - Glass, Philip, concert programs, press, 1971-1972 (5.13)
    - Lacoste School of the Arts, benefit, 1990 April (6.1 - 6.2)
    - Morgan, Priscilla, 90th birthday party, 2009 October (6.3 - 6.6)
    - Municipal Art Society, Noguchi, President's Medal, 1985 October (6.7)
    - Noguchi Garden Museum Opening, logistics, 1985 (6.8)
    - Noguchi Museum Benefit, Vermont Studio School, 1986 June (6.9)
    - Noguchi Museum Spring Benefit, with Patti Smith, 2012 May (6.10)
    - Noguchi Museum, Storm King Sculpture Park, 1985 November (6.11)
  - FULLER, R. BUCKMINSTER
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, ceremony program, 1968-05-28 (7.1)
    - Buckminster Fuller Centennial Celebration, seating charts, notes, 1995-11-09 (44.6)
    - Buckminster Fuller Institute Newsletter, correspondence, 1984 (7.2)
    - Correspondence, to/from RBF/PM, 1968-1971 (7.3 - 7.4)
    - Critique by Shoji Sadad re New Yorker article on RBF, 2008 June (7.5)
    - Fundraising efforts, 1980 (7.6)
    - Futurist, Journal of Forecasts, Trends and Ideas, 1969 February (7.7)
    - How Little I Know, TS, with annotations by RBF, inscribed to PM, 1966 October (7.8)
    - Keynote address, text, Vision 65, Southern Illinois University, 1965 October (7.9)
    - Letterhead, The R. Buckminster Fuller Centennial Celebration, 1995 November (7.10)
    - NY Studio School, Buckminster Fuller lecture, logistics, promotion, 1971 February (44.7)
    - Nine Chains to the Moon, photocopies of inscribed title page to PM, 1967 October (7.11)
    - Offprints, 1932-1969 (7.12 - 7.14)
    - Planetary Planning, New Delhi, lecture text, promotional materials, 1969 (7.15)
    - Poetry, by RBF, TS and photocopies, 1970-1971 (7.16 - 7.17)
    - President Makarios, statement, Nicosia, Cyprus, 1966 July (7.18)
    - Profile of the Industrial Revolution (7.19)
    - Promotional, printed materials, 1971 (7.20)
    - Schedule of lectures and projects, autobiographical RBF letter (photocopy), 1951-1956 (7.21)
    - Sketch, Deliberately Non-Straight Line, to Isamu Noguchi (photocopy), 1967-05-24 (7.22)
    - Sketch, Fuller's Principle of Irreversibility, signed by RBF, 1972-11-24 (44.8)
    - Sketch, Mini Earth Suspended Over East River, drawn on American Airlines Boarding Pass, 1971-04-26 (7.23)
    - Spoleto, RBF exhibit, budgets, logistics, correspondence, 1966-1968 (7.24 - 7.25)
    - Spoletosphere, logistics, 1971 (7.26)
    - Spoletosphere, notes, drawings, prints, 1967-1969 (44.9)
    - The Synergetical World of R. Buckminster Fuller, offprint signed by RBF, 1973 November (7.27)
    - Travel itineraries, 1970-1975 (8.1)
    - Wheelwright, Joseph - correspondence, travel itineraries, 1976-1982 (8.2)
    - World Man Center, promotional material, 1966 (8.3)
  - GENERAL
    - A Play for Television, TS, by Tad Mosel, undated (8.4)
    - Albany TV, shareholder minutes (8.5)
    - Annual account, Lisa de Kooning Trust, 2009 (8.6)
    - Apartment appraisals, inventories, 1957-1986 (8.7)
    - Bouche, Rene, correspondence, sketches, 1954-1957 (44.1 - 44.2)
    - Boys Harbor Art Show, event logistics, 1991 June (8.8)
    - Christmas lists, gifts, cards rec'd, 1952-1953 (44.3)
    - de Kooning, Lisa, bills paid by PM, 1985-1989 (8.9 - 8.11)
    - de Kooning, Lisa, funeral logistics, 2012 December (8.12)
    - de Kooning, Willem - conservancy office space plans, 1990 (8.13)
    - de Kooning, Willem, conservancy office space plans, 1997 March (8.14)
    - Del Turco, Lorenzo, 1971 (8.15)
    - Guild Hall, Willem de Kooning event logistics, 1994 June (8.16)
    - Khanal, Puna Ram (Pushkak), 2003 (9.1)
    - Lacoste School of the Arts, 1985-2002 (9.2)
    - Letterhead stationery, Priscilla Morgan, undated (9.3)
    - Lists, notes, circa 1950-1959 (9.4)
    - Massie, Robert, 1971 December (9.5)
    - McGrath, Earl, 1963 (9.6)
    - Nickrenz, Elizabeth, poetry, 1987 (9.7)
    - Phone logs, 1976-1992 (9.8 - 10.3)
    - Player, Willis, 1968-1972 (10.4)
    - Pritchett, Florence, 1964-1965 (10.5)
    - Pushkar, Puna Ram, 2003-2007 (10.6)
    - Robbins, Jerome, budgets, travel, 1978 January (10.7)
    - Robison, Paula, 1983-2009 (10.8)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1966 (10.9)
    - Rosentiel, Elizabeth, 1974-1975 (10.10)
    - Dadao, Shoji, undated (10.11)
    - Scelsi, Giancarlo, 1977 (10.12)
    - Schlumberger, Madam Merre, 1973-1974 (10.13)
    - Schoelkopf, Caroline, 1983 (10.14)
    - Segerstrom, Henry, 2005-2006 (10.15 - 11.2)
    - Shapiro, Nathasha, 1976 (11.3)
    - Shapiro, Tina, 1990-1991 (11.4)
    - Sketches, artwork unidentified, undated (44.4)
    - Snyder, Alexandra, memories of Noguchi, undated (11.5)
    - Sterne, Hedda, 1975-1995 (11.6)
    - Tully, Alice, 1971 (11.7)
    - Urban Arts Corps Theatre, 1974 (11.8)
    - Vanderbilt, Gloria, 2003 (11.9)
    - Vassar, Priscilla Morgan exhibit logistics, 1988-2007 (11.10- 11.11)
    - Ventouras, Octavio, 2011-2012 (11.12)
    - Vogue, article re Priscilla Morgan, 2007 (11.13)
    - Vreeland, Tim, manuscripts, 2005-2006 (11.14 - 11.15)
    - Wadsworth, Susan, 2009 (11.16)
    - Wieners, John, handmade book, 1965 (11.17)
    - Wilson, Robert, includes signed book, Paradiso, 1973-2010 (11.18 - 11.19, 12.1 - 12.2)
    - Woffard, Harris, 1970-1975 (12.3)
  - HARLEM THEATER WORKSHOP
    - Board, reports, meeting agendas, minutes, 1968-1972 (12.4 - 12.8)
    - Budgets, correspondence, 1967-1971 (12.9 - 12.12)
    - Closing documents, real estate, 1970 October (44.5)
    - Condemnation of the Latino Theater, letter from P. Morgan, 1971 May (12.13)
    - Corporation by-laws, 1968 (12.14)
    - Correspondence to/from Priscilla Morgan, 1968-1972 (12.15 - 12.18)
    - East Harlem Triangle Neighborhood Development, correspondence, 1971 May (12.19)
    - NYC Housing and Development, correspondence, 1968-1971 (12.20)
  - LEGAL
    - Business certificate, Priscilla Morgan Agency, 1953 June (13.1)
    - Contracts, Liebling Wood, William Morris, Priscilla Morgan Agency, 1951-1964 (13.2 - 13.5)
    - Estate of Marian Barradale Morgan, 1961-1964 (13.6)
    - Marriage certificate, divorce documentation, will (Margaret Hotchkiss), 1949-1955 (13.7)
    - Real estate, Bucks County property, 1956-1964 (13.8 - 13.11)
    - Will, Priscilla Morgan, correspondence, drafts, notes, 1968-2006 (13.12 - 13.13)
  - MENOTTI
    - A Happy Ending, script, film production correspondence, 1963 (14.1 - 14.2)
    - Amahl and the Night Visitors, agreements, programs, 1968-1972 (44.10, 14.3)
    - American Center for Students and Artists, Paris, 1976-1977 (44.11)
    - American Symphony Tripoli Concerto, 1970 October (14.4)
    - Bell Telephone Hour Broadcast, Menotti documentary, 1966 (14.5)
    - Concert tour logistics, Klaus Kolmar, 1963-1965 (14.6)
    - The Consul, NYC Opera, agreement, notes, 1966, 1974 (14.7, 44.12)
    - Contracts, CBS TV, 1962-1963 (14.8)
    - Contracts, The Last Superman; The Saint of Bleeker Street, 1959-1965 (44.13 - 44.14)
    - Contracts, Vanessa, 1964 (14.9)
    - Correspondence, notes, press clippings, 1965- 1973 (14.10)
    - Correspondence, notes, itineraries, programs, 1971-1974 (14.11)
    - Correspondence to/from Priscilla Morgan, 1968-1975 (14.12)
    - Fort Worth, TX, Spoleto Festival, 1966 (14.13)
    - Globolinks, fundraising, press clippings, Ray Stark, 1970-1971 (45.1 - 45.4)
    - Globolinks, City Center, Hamburg, Santa Fe, 1968-1971 (14.14 - 14.18)
    - Labyrinth Corporation, first board meeting minutes, 1964 April (14.19)
    - Labyrinth, certificate of incorporation, scripts, 1963-1964 (15.1)
    - Last Savage, L'Ultimo Superuomo, musical score title page, signed by Gian Carlo Menotti, undated (45.5)
    - The Leper, programs, promotion, correspondence, 1968-1970 (15.2 - 15.3)
    - Letter, re: Harlem Theater Workshop ceasing efforts, 1972 Februar (15.4)
    - Madame Aupic, agreements, notes, 1958-1965 (15.5, 45.6)
    - Maria Golovin, opera, 1965 (15.6)
    - Martin's Lie, production logistics, 1964 (15.7)
    - Martin's Lie, script photocopies, 1964 (15.8)
    - Martin's Lie, correspondence, budgets, logistics, 1963-1967 (15.9 -15.11, 45.7, 45.8)
    - Menotti, Gian Carlo, bio, resume, 1974 (15.12)
    - Menotti, Gian Carlo, memorial, 2007 February (15.13)
    - The Most Important Man in the World, NYC Opera press clippings, 1971 (45.9)
    - Notes, travel expenses, 1964-1971 (15.14 - 15.16)
    - Of Two Worlds, Spoleto proposal, Walter Wanger project, 1962-1963 (15.17)
    - Press clippings, 1971 (15.18)
    - Speech, commencement, Curtis Institute of Music, 1965 May (15.19)
    - Spoleto budgets, 1963 (15.20)
    - Spoletosphere, Festival of Two Worlds, press clippings, 1967 (15.21)
    - Symphony of the New World, promotion, 1971 (15.22)
    - Tamu Tamu, Opera Studebaker Theatre, promotion, 1973 (15.23)
  - MPM PRODUCTIONS
    - Bio file, Morgan, Priscilla, Manulis, Matin, Penn, Arthur, undated (16.1)
    - Breece George - notes, correspondence, 1981 (16.2)
    - Film, TV script research, circa 1980-1989 (16.3)
    - Gilchrist, Ellen, MS submissions, 1989-1995 (16.4)
    - Herman, Jerry, notes, press clippings, 1992 (16.5)
    - Horovitiz, Israel, notes, correspondence, 1978-1979 (16.6)
    - Love in All Its Disguises, synopsis, by Norman Rosten, notes, correspondence, 1983-1990 (16.7)
    - New Yorker, Talk of the Town, George Trow, marked-up galley, 1971-03-13 (16.8)
    - Partnership agreement, 1978-1988 (16.9)
    - Penn, Arthur, bio file, 1980 (16.10)
    - Press clippings, press releases, 1978 (16.11)
    - Requests for collaboration, correspondence, 1978 (16.12)
    - Script reports, 1978-1989 (16.13)
    - Script research, 1980-1990 (16.14)
    - Tournier, Michael, press clippings, memos, 1988-1990 (16.15)
    - Wally Cafe, theatrical production, negotiations, 1979 (16.16)
  - NOGUCHI, ISAMU
    - Akari light sculptures, Isamu Noguchi handwritten artist statement, undated (45.10)
    - Akari light sculptures, marketing materials, 1990 (17.1)
    - Akari light sculptures, retail price list, 1973 (17.2)
    - Art for Senator McGovern, donation, 1972 (17.3)
    - Artist statement, Two Stone Gardens, Yale University, Chase Manhattan Bank, undated (17.4)
    - Autobiography, notes, correspondence, research, 1960-1964 (17.5)
    - Awards, honors given, programs and correspondence, 1969-1974 (45.11)
    - Book, regarding Noguchi childhood, by Tobi Tobias, includes letter, and critique by Noguchi, 1972-1973 (17.6)
    - Book statement, Tobi Tobias, including carbon copy of Noguchi correspondence, 1969-1974 (17.7)
    - Budgets, office expenses, 1970-1984 (17.8)
    - Catalog raisonne proposal, 2008-2010 (17.9)
    - Centennial birthday event logistics, 2004 (17.10 - 17.11)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, Tokyo, correspondence to/from Noguchi and David Rockefeller, 1972 (17.12)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, Tokyo, letter handwritten, from Noguchi to Gordon Bunshaft, 1973-07-16 (45.12)
    - Correspondence, administrative, from Noguchi, 1971-1976 (17.13)
    - Correspondence, administrative, to Noguchi, 1968-1988 (17.14)
    - Detroit, imaginary landscapes, including TS re Walter Dusenbery, by Isamu Noguchi, 1972 (17.15)
    - Graham, Martha, repertoire lists, notes, 1973-1974 (45.13)
    - Horace E. Dodge and Son Foundation, Detroit MI, 1971-1974 (45.14)
    - Film documentary projects, 1972-1986 (17.16)
    - Fountain and Plaza, Cambridge, MA, 1973, 1974 (17.17)
    - Gallery correspondence, Wight, Pace, Walker Art Center, Marlborough, 1968-1990 (17.18)
    - Gimpel Hanover Gallery, Switzerland, includes Noguchi correspondence, 1971-1973 (17.19)
    - Glass, Philip, benefit logistics, 1996 (17.20)
    - Harvard Graduate School, Noguchi Museum, 1989-1992 (18.1)
    - Hayden Herrera, Japan travel, 2004 (18.2)
    - Hayden Herrera, Noguchi biography budgets, contract, 2005-2007 (18.3)
    - Hayden Herrera, fundraising, 2005-2006 (18.4)
    - Hayden Herrera agreement, correspondence, 1993-2005 (18.5)
    - Hiroi, Tsutomu, book preface, by Isamu Noguchi, 1972 (18.6)
    - Hunter, Sam, book, letter of agreement, 1977 (18.7)
    - Japan House Gallery, 1969-1974 (18.8)
    - Miyake, Issey, correspondence, 1996 (18.9)
    - Morgan, Priscilla, compensation request, Noguchi Museum, 1990- 1995 (18.10)
    - Mure Museum, 1990-1992 (18.11 - 18.13)
    - National Gallery of Art, exhibition, "Unknown Bird", 1973-1974 (18.14)
    - Noguchi Foundation, board minutes, 1990 (18.15)
    - Noguchi Foundation, consultancy, correspondence, meeting notes, 1987-2004 (18.16)
    - Noguchi Memorial, Priscilla Morgan speech text, 1989 (18.17)
    - Noguchi Studio, Mure-Cho, Japan, 1993-1994 (18.18)
    - Notes, Japan travel, 1971-1973 (18.19)
    - Preservation efforts in Japan, 2004 (18.20)
    - Problems of Modern Sculpture, TS, Noguchi lecture, Yale, 1948 (19.1)